## LEAH CARDOZ

they/them/theirs | Brooklyn, NY | 516-554-1060 | leahcardoz@gmail.com Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github | Blog

## **FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Full stack software engineer with a knack for eye-catching, user-friendly web design. With a decade of experience supporting C-Level executives in the live music industry, I excel in delivering optimal results with professionalism in high-pressure environments. As a proud member of the AAPI and LGBTQ+ communities eager to begin my career in tech, I look forward to expanding my skill set at a workplace that values integrity and embraces community.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, ReactJS, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Material UI, Semantic UI, Git, RESTful APIs, Figma, Netlify

#### TECHNICAL APPLICATIONS

## Gig Prints - Github | Demo

A hub for touring bands and poster designers to discover each other and connect to create concert posters together.

- Utilized a React frontend and Rails backend to respectively facilitate and harness CRUD actions for three models.
- Implemented authentication and authorization with a secure login/logout using password encryption and sessions.
- Pioneered an interactive frontend complete with react-router client-side routes and uniformly styled with Semantic UI.
- Compiled extensive seed data for the models into a custom built API utilizing foreign keys for the joiner model.

#### Engine-Ear. - Github | Demo

A social media app solely for software engineers to connect, network, and post content about anything coding-related.

- Created a user-friendly React interface employing Ruby on Rails for authenticated backend capabilities.
- Utilized six models via ActiveRecord including a self join table with alias ids for the user-to-user relationship.
- Strengthened signup and login security by using hashing, salting, and bcrypt to protect user data.
- Implemented a feature to filter user content by relevant tags such as job postings, projects, and blog posts.

#### The Archive - Github (Frontend) | Github (Backend) | Demo

An application where users can showcase and submit their favorite screenprint artists and their prints.

- Architected a full stack application from the ground up, utilizing React for frontend and Ruby Sinatra API for backend.
- Engineered RESTful Routing by leveraging ActiveRecord associations to incorporate methods into controllers.
- Developed an API from scratch with full CRUD routing capabilities for two interactive models.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **City Winery International**

New York, NY

Executive Assistant to CEO/Founder

05/2021 - 09/2022

- Efficiently streamlined the CEO's workflow by organizing schedules, owning projects, managing inboxes, shadow-writing emails, collaborating in cross-functional teams, and giving tours to investors and press.
- Advanced the company's growth by conducting market research for location expansion, authoring and editing board decks for investor meetings, and fostering partnerships with local businesses on behalf of the CEO.
- Independently spearheaded large-scale events –including yearly management off-site conferences and numerous benefit galas- sourcing event spaces, arranging travel and hotel accommodations, and planning menus.

#### **High Road Touring**

Sausalito, CA 06/2015 - 07/2018

Artist Agent Assistant

- Convened with the CEO and a team of agents to effectively book concert tours for over 300 artists in America.
- Supervised the Contracts and Earnings Departments, vetting all signed contracts, immigration and insurance documents, and calculating and assuring accurate yearly earnings for all touring artists.
- Managed the administrative department by screening calls, organizing meetings, and training all new hires.

### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School

New York, NY

Full Stack Software Engineering Program

10/2022 - 01/2023

University of California, Berkeley - Walter A. Haas School of Business

Berkeley, CA 08/2011 - 05/2015

Bachelor of Arts, Business Administration and Management